Guide to the The Review of Contemporary Fiction/Dalkey Archive Press: records, 1980-1990
Department of Special Collections
The Review of Contemporary Fiction/Dalkey Archive Press: records,
1980-1990
M0507
John O'Brien
30 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
John O'Brien founded The Review of Contemporary Fiction (RCF) in 1980 and established the Dalkey Archive Press three years later. Since its inaugural Spring 1981 issue, RCF has appeared with exact regularity three times a year. Each number is devoted to one or two contemporary figures, predominantly American and British but also some European writers as well. The contents of a typical number include original work by the writer featured, an interview with him or her, a memoir or other biographical reminiscence by literary colleagues, and several extended critical articles. The Dalkey Archive Press began as a modest adjunct to RCF, issuing reprints of books by writers featured in the journal, or associated with those writers. Then in 1986, O'Brien began issuing original works.
Administrative Information
Access
Gilbert Sorrentino material is partially restricted. Stanford holds no copyright to the material in the collection, only physical rights.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 1988, 1989 and 1990.
Provenance
Purchased, 1988, 1989 and 1990.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
Correspondence, literary manuscripts, typescripts, proofs and final copies, uncorrected galleys, as well as interviews with contemporary writers.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Aas-Rouxparis, Nicole, $1942-; Abbey, Edward, 1927-; Abbott, Keith, 1944-; Abel, Lionel.; Acker, Kathy, 1948-; Ackroyd, Peter.; Aldridge, John.; Almansi, Guido, 1931-; Ansen, Alan.; Antin, David.; Araâujo, Helena, 1934-; Baneham, Sam, 1947-; Banks, John, 1919-; Bann, Stephen.; Baralt, Luce Lâopez.; Barilli, Renato.; Barnes, Dick, 1932-; Barth, John.; Bastos, Marâia Luisa.; Baumgart, Reinhard, 1929-; Beekman, E. M., 1929-; Bellos, David.; Benet, Juan.; Berger-Locher, Gertrude.; Berry, Eliot, 1949-; Bertholf, Robert J.; Bieder, MaryEllen.; Bishop, Thomas.; Blaser, Robin.; Bogan, Jim.; Bourjaily, Vance Nye.; Bowering, George, 1935-; Bowers, John, 1928-; Bowles, Paul, 1910-; Boyer, Philipe, 1931-; Bradbury, Malcolm, 1932-; Brautigan, Richard.; Braverman, Kate Ellen, 1947-; Britton, Celia.; Bronk, William.; Brooke-Rose, Christine, 1923-; Charters, Ann.; Châenetier, Marc, 1946-; Christensen, Paul, 1943-; Churchill, Thomas B.L.; Clark, Tom.; Codrescu, Andrei, 1946-; Cohen, Keith.; Coleman, Wanda.; Cook, Carole, 1941-; Cook, Albert Spaulding.; Cott, Jonathan.; Cortazâar, Julio.; Coyne, John.; Creeley, Robert, 1926-; Damisch, Hubert.; Dardess, George.; Davenport, Guy.; Davidson, Arnold E., 1936-; Davis, David J. (David John), 1875-1954.; Dawson, Fielding, 1930-; Debaisieux, Martine.; Defanti, Charles, 1942-; De Lauretis, Teresa.; Dâiaz Migoyo, Gonzalo, 1941-; Dillon, Millicent.; Ditsky, John.; Doctorow, E.L., 1931-; Donaldson, Scott.; Dorn, Edward.; Dowell, Coleman.; Duer, David.; Dukore, Margaret Mitchell.; Duncan, Alistair.; Duvert, Tony.; Duytschaever, Joris.; Eastlake, William.; Eckstein, Barbara J.; Elkin, Stanley, 1930-; Elman, Richard.; Emerson, Stephen.; Emery, Mary Lou.; Emmett, Paul.; Enslin, Theodore.; Epstein, Leslie.; Estrin, Barbara L., 1942-; Everson, William, 1912-; Fabre, Michel.; Fallon, Peter, 1951-; Feliciano, Margarita, 1938-; Figes, Eva.; Fink, Guido, 1930-; Fleisher, Michael, 1952-; Fletcher, John, 1937-; Fogel, Stanley.; Foucault, Michel.; Fox, Robert E., 1937-; Francescato, Martha Paley.; Friedenberg, Edgar Zodiag, 1921-; Fuentes, Carlos.; Gaddis, William, 1922-; Garfield, Evelyn Picon.; Ghose, Zulfikar, 1935-; Goytisolo, Juan.; Greer, Germaine, 1939-; Grossman, Edith, 1936-; Guest, Barbara.; Gunn, Thomas.; Halpern, Daniel, 1945-; Hawkes, John.; Higgins, Aidan, 1927-; Hoyem, Andrew.; Kerrigan, Anthony.; Lane, Helen.; Leary, Timothy Francis, 1920-; Lehman, David.; Lessing, Doris May, 1919-; Liddy, James, 1934-; Malamud, Bernard.; Malin, Irving.; Markfield, Wallace.; Markson, David.; Mathews, Harry, 1930-; McElroy, Joseph.; McGonigle, Thomas.; McManus, James.; McPheron, William.; Metcalf, Paul C.; Mosley, Nicholas, 1923-; Motte, Warren F.; Mottram, Eric.; Murdoch, Iris.; Napora, Joe, 1944-; Navarre, Yves, 1940-; Oates, Joyce Carol.; O'Brien, John.; O'Brien, Michael.; Ollier, Claude.; Olson, Toby.; Ortega, Julio.; Otten, Anna.; Pâerez, Janet.; Pinget, Robert.; Pugh, Anthony Cheal.; Reed, Ishmael, 1938-; Roudiez, Leon Samuel, 1917-; Rower, Ann.; Rushdie, Salman.; Selby, Hubert, Jr.; Simon, Claude.; Sorrentino, Gilbert.; Stephens, Michael.; Tindall, Kenneth, 1937-; Valenzuela, Luisa, 1938-; Walsh, Joy.; Wright, Barbara, 1935-; Zurbrugg, Nicholas.; Dalkey Archive Press.; The Review of Contemporary Fiction.;. 0$aAmerican literature--20th century.
Collection Contents
- Series I: Review of Contemporary Fiction
  - Sorrentino
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1971-1974 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1980 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1981 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1982 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sorrentino/O'Brien correspondence1985-1987 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - North Point Press Cataloges (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Miscellaneous articles, clippings, publications sent in correspondence (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Issue Correspondence: Antin - Elman (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Issue Correspondence: Fleisher - MacLochlainn (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Issue Correspondence: Mercier - Wieners (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Issue: Sorrentino Interview (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Preliminary Table of Contents (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Cover and Contents (title-p.4) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Sorrentino Interview (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - "The Act of Creation and Its Artifact" - Gilbert Sorentino (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - "From Work in Process, Blue Pastoral" - Gilbert Sorrentino (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - "Sorrentino's Past" - Toby Olsen (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - "In the song/ of the alphabet: Gilbert Sorrentino's Splendide Hotel" - Sharon Thesen (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - "Every Man His Voice" - Patrick McCarthy (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - "'Yes, We Have No Bananas': Gilbert Sorrentino's The Orangery" - Marie Russell (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - "A Marvellous Gift: Gilbert Sorrentino's Fiction" - Max Eilenberg (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - "A Short Defense of Plagiary" - G.L. Bruns (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - "Antony Lamont in Search of Gilbert Sorrentino: Character and Mulligan Stew" - Donald J. Greiner (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - "The Sky Changes: A Journey into the Uncouscious and a Road into the Novels of Gilbert Sorrentino" --Dr. Paul Emmett (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Blue Indigo" - Lowell Dunlap (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - "The Reality Changes" -Leon S. Roudiez (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - "Gilbert Sorrentino's Aberration of Starlight" -Coleman Dowell (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - "Gilbert Sorrentino and Mulligan Stew" -Nicholas Mosley (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - "Reading Gil Sorrentino" - Richard Elman (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - "Xmas as in Merry" -Robert Creeley (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - "Adam and Eve on a Raft" -Kenneth Tindall (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - "On Giving Up Fictioneering" -Bernard Share (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - "Sorrentino's Steelwork..." - preliminary articles (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "The Parody Novel: Sterne's Tristram Shandy" - Richard Sheldon (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Contributors (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Book Reviews: Overview (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Book Reviews (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Text Copy: Reviews (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Text Copy: Reviews (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Text Copy: pp. 5-27 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Text Copy: pp. 28-38 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Text Copy: pp. 39-47 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Text Copy: pp. 48-61 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Text Copy: pp. 62-80 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Text Copy: pp. 81-95 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Text Copy: pp. 96-112 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Text Copy: pp. 113-129 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Text Copy: pp. 130-152 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Text Copy: pp. 153-170 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Text Copy: pp. 171-189 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Text Copy: pp. 190-211 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Text Copy: pp. 212-232 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - "Psychic DiSIrEnberIng and Staying Sane: The Fiction of Gilbert Sorrentino" - Eric Mottrain (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - "On Mulligan Stew" - St. John Sweeney (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - "The Person of Fiction, The Fiction of Person" (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - "Rose Theatre" (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - "The Bronc People" - Author unknown (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Metcalf / Selby
    - Correspondence: Atchity - Brossard (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence Buckeye - DeFanti: (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence: Enslin - Metcalf (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence: Napora - Olson (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Oppenheimer - Wertime (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Contents, Book received, Contributors (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Interview with Metcalf (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - "Interview with Paul Metcalf" (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - "Paul Metcalf and the Documetary Narrative" - George Butterick (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - "Notes for a Festshrift on Paul Metcalf"- Richard Grossinger (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - "From Melville to Olson to Metcalf: The Double Play"-TQU thurchill (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - "Local Universe" - Vincent Ferrini (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - "For Paul Metcalf" - Anmiiel Alcalay (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - "Re: incarnation-Patagoni, U.S. Dept. of the Interior, the body of knowledge and going nowhere fast" - Napora (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "Paul Metcalf.. .A Very Personal Appreciation" -Theodore Enslin (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Travels Thru the Interior: notes toward a structural analysis of Paul Metcalf"-Alex Gildzen (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "Mr. Metcalf and the Savage Mind" - Don Byrd (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "Paul Metcalf Delivers the News" - Harry Lewis (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "The Thrill of thoosing: Paul Metcalf and the Power of Not-So-Blackness" - Charles DeFanti (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "Language and Materials in Paul Metcalf's Art"-Jonh O'Brien (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Interview with Selby (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Interview with Hubert Selby (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Gilbert Sorrentino: "The Art of Hubert Selby" (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - "Addenda 1981: After Last Exit to Brooklyn"-Gilbert Sorrentino (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - "Selby' s Yahoos: The Brooklyn Breed - A dialogue of the Mind with Itself" - Jack Byrne (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - "Free Like the Rest of Us: Violation and Despair in Hubert Selby' s Novels" - Eric Mottram (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Herman and Hubert: The Odd Couple - Paul Metcalf (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - The Fishing at Coney Island: Hubert Selby, Jr. and the Colt of Authenticity - Kenneth Tindall (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Some Preliminary Notes Toward a Study of Selby -Robert Buckeye (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - The Materials of Art in Hubert Selby -John O'Brien (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - The Mirror of Man - Roland Binet (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Hubert Selby, Jr.: The Poet of Prose Masters -Michael Stephens (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - "Memories - Joel Oppenheimer (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Hubert Selby's Requiem for a Dream: A Primer of Vision - Kenneth John Atchity (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - On the Question of Style in Hubert Selby, Jr.'s Fiction - Richard Wertima (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Some Things I Want to Say About Hubert Selby's Work - Harry Lewis (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Potebnya -Richard Sheldon (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Book Reviews (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Typist's Copy: Table of contents - p.272 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 273-314 (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 315-363 (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 364-413 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 414-end (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - Text copy: Title page and Table of Contents (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Text copy: pp. 273-314 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Text copy: pp. 315-363 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Text copy: pp. 364-413 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Text copy: pp. 414-end (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Woolf / Markfield
    - Correspondence: Abbey-Bender (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence: Bowering-Emerson (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence: Emmett-Moore (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence: Mottram-Tindall (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Playing the Kite - Kenneth Tindall (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - God and Famous - Kenneth Tindall (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - The Hanmer of Wednesday - Kenneth Tindall (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Book Reviews (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - the beginning - Thomas McGonigle (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - From the Middle - Thomas McGonigle (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - A much later note, on John-Juan - Edward Doon (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - All Things Considered" in Douglas Woolf -John O'Brien (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Douglas Woolf's Ideal Fictions - Brian Stonehill (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - The Great Mother in the Fiction of Douglas Woolf: Ma in Ya!" - Paul Emmett (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - First Prize - Robert Creeley (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Ornamental Prose: Andrei Bely - Richard Sheldon (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Ya! Ya! Ya! Ya!... - Lowell Dunlap (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Douglas Woolf' s Escape from Enclosure -Eric Mottram (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - 16 Paragraphs on Douglas Woolf - Keith Abbott (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Teitlebaum' s Window... - Jack Byrne (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Douglas Woolf's 'Bank Dey' - George Bowering (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Wrestling with Idealization: Wallace Markfield' s You Could Live if They Let You -Stephen L. Bender (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Enigma of Unpopularity and Critical Neglect... -Melvin J. Freedman (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Interview with Wallace Markfield (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "'Whoosh and Gaah: the New York Intellectuals..."-Sanford Pinsker (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Typist's copy: pp. 1-44 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Typist's copy: pp.45-87 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Typist's copy: pp. 88-128 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Typist's copy: pp. 129-172 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Typist's copy: pp. 173-end (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Gaddis / Mosley
    - Correspondence: Ackroyd-Eilenberg (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence: Fellows-Kuehl (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence: Lathrop-Moore (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence Mosley-Weisenburger (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - "Interview with William Gaddis" - John Kuehl and Steven Moore (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - William Gaddis's JR: The Novel of Babel" -Carl D. Malmgreen (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - "Paper Currencies: Reading William Gaddis" -Steven Weisenburger (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - "The paper Empires and Empirical Fictions of William Gaddis" -Joel Dana Black (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "Comic-Ironic Parallels in William Gaddis' The Recognitions" - Stephen paul Martin (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - "What did you say Mister Gaddis? form in William Gaddis's JR" -Michael Boccia (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "Vulnerability and Aggression: Characters and Objects in The Recognitions" - Stephen Paul Martin (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - "False Gold to Forge: The Forger Behind Wyatt Gwyon" -Tom Sawyer (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - "William Gaddis: A Selected Bibliography" - Steven Moore (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "An Interview with Nicholas Mosley" -John O'Brien (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - "Faulkner's Fables" -Nicholas Mosley (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - Impossible Accidents: Nicholas Mosley" - Francis Booth (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "Sleight of Language" -John Banks (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - "It's Like a Story: Mosley's Impossible Object" -John O'Brien (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - "Private Madness and Natalie Natalia" -John Banks (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - "Contrived Chaos: Catastrophe Practice and Godelian Incompleteness" -John Banks (Box 7, Folder 33)
    - "Toward A Theory of the Comic" -Viktor Shklovskey (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Typists Copy: pp.2-44 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Typists Copy: pp.45-86 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Typists Copy: pp. 87-123 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Typists Copy: pp.124-168 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Typists Copy: Book Reviews (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Text Copy: pp.1-44 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Text Copy: pp. 45-86 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Text Copy: 87-123 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Text Copy: 124-171 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Bowles / Dowell
    - Correspondence: Bowles-Dowell (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence: Duytshaever-Hunt (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence: Lesser-White (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - "Drastic Points" -Irving Malin (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - "A Journey in Search of paul Bowles" -Paul Metcalf (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - "From Metcalf to Bowles to peabody" -Corespondences for Bowles Issue (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - "Let it Come Down and Inner Geography" -Wayne Pounds (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - "Paul Bowles: Past and Present" -Tim Hunt (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - "Approaching Paul Bowles" -Jack Collings (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - "Paul Bowles and 'The Frozen Fields of Vision'" -Lawrence D. Stewart (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - "Paul Bowles and the Perception of Evil" -Robert Hauptmann (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - "Endings and The Sheltering Sky" -Stephen Emerson (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - "Paul Bowles: 'Do Not Appropriate My Object'" -Linda S. Wells (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Interview with Coleman Dowell (Box 8, Folder 24)
    - "Literary Balcomb Greene" -ColemannDowell (Box 8, Folder 25)
    - "White Into black" -Colemann Dowell (Box 8, Folder 26)
    - "Thoughts on White on Black on White" -Edmund White (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - "Colemann Dowell's Short Stories" -Meriam Fuchs (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - "Colemann Dowell" -Balcomb Green (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - "Exorcism and Grace: A Study of Androgyny in Island People" -Stephen-Paul Martin (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - "Miss Ethel and Mr. Dowell" -John and Linda Kandel Kuehl (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - "Pushy Jews and Aging Queens: Imaginary People in Two Novels by Colemann Dowell" -Thom Gunn (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - "Coleman Dowell's Frame-up: What Miss Ethel did Last Winter" -Jack Byrne (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Book Reviews (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Typist's copy: pp.1-50 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Typist's copy: pp. 51-101 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Typist's copy: pp.102-148 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Typist's copy: pp.149-183 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Text Copy: Cover (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Text copy: pp.1-50 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Text Copy: pp.51-101 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Text Copy: pp.102-148 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Text Copy: pp.149-end (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Eastlake / Higgins
    - Correspondence: Abbey-Dorm (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence: Eastlake-Mocaffezy (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence:McGonigle 1981 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Correspondence: McGonigle 1982 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Correspondence: McPheron-Wylder (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Interview with William Eastlake; Questionnaire (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Wilain Eastlake: Para Mi Amigo" - Edward Abbey (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "The Southwest Novels of William Eastlake"-Gerald Haslam (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Poetry, Abstraction, and the Comedy of Dream: William Eastlake's Portrait of an Artist with 26 Horses"-Jaires R. Lindroth (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Style in Eastlake's Southwestern Novels: Personal Visions and Digressions" - Larry McCaffery (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "William Eastlake: Satiric Voice Looking for a Form" -Delbert E. Wylder (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "Eastlake: The Artist as Director of Revels"-Albert Wachtel (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Cowboys and Indians" - Robert Creeley (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Portrait of a Horse with Twenty-Six Artists"-George BcMering (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Debunking the Myth of the West" - Bathara E. Barnes (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "The Limits of Survival with the Weapons of Humor:William Eastlake" - Eric Mottram (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "The Critical Reception of William Eastlake"-William McPheron (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "William Eastlake: A Checklist" - William McPheron (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "The Heroe's Portion: Chaos or Anarchy in the Caltic Twoilet" - Aidan Higgins (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "From Bornholrn Night-Ferry" - Aidan Higgins (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "Aidan Higgins: Figures in Landscape"-Michael Mollen (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Down from the Balcony" - Bernard Share (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Scenes from a Receding Past" - John O'Brien (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Notes on the Wandering Celt: Aidan Higgin 's Balcony of Europe" - Janes Liddy (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Aidan Higgins: A Political Dimension" - Sam Baneham (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Towards Bornholm Night-Ferry and Texts for the Air: A rereading of Aidan Higgins - Dermot Healy (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Form as an Extension of Content: 'their existence in my eyes" - Robert Buckeye (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "Notes on Higgin' s Ladies of Springfield House"-Jack Byrne (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "Parsing Love's Canplainte: Aidan Higgins on the Need to Name" - Sean Golden (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Let the Dead Bury the Dead: a prepared slide from St. Patrick' s Day, Dublin,1974"-Thomas McGonigle (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "Evgeny Onegin (Pusbkin and Sterne)"-Viktor Sbklovsky (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Book Reviews (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - "Imaginary Meadows" - Aidan Higgins (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Typist' s Copy: pp. 4-17 (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Typist' s Copy: pp.18-40 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Typist's Copy: pp.42-67 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Typist's Copy: pp.68-105 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 108-14 1 (3 copies) (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 141-174 (3 copies) (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Typist's Copy: (partial copies) pp. 175-209 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Typist's Copy: pp. 221-237 (2 copies) (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Text Copy: cover-p.3 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Text Copy: pp. 4-41 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Text Copy: pp. 42-83 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Text Copy: pp 84-123 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Text Copy:pp. 124-163 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Text Copy: pp. 164-209 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Text Copy: pp. 210-252 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - "Winter is coming" by Aidan Higgins (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Kerouac / Pinget
    - Correspondence: Abbott - Bishop (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence: Blanchot - Durert (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence: Fagin - Johnson, Ronna (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence: Kart-Otten (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence: Platier - Sturrock (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence: Taliman - Woods (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Kerouac" - William Burroughs (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - "Doctor Sax: The Origins of Vision in the Duluoz Leend" - Ronna Johnson (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - "Jack Kerouac' s 'Jazz America' or Who Was Roger Beloit?" - Larry Kart (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - "Kerouac' s Harmonious Combination of Elements: The Long Symphonic Sentence" - Joy Walsh (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - "The Misreading of Kerouac" - Tim Hunt (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - "Kerouac and Jazz" - Jim Burns (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - "Diluoz and Faust" - George Rideout (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "A Preface to Visions of Cody" - Eric Mottraiu (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - "Tender Hearts in Boulder" - John Clellon Holmes (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - "Synaesthesia, Synchronisity, and Syncopation"-Regina Weineich (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - "Jack Kerouac: Roman Catholic Conscience and The Body" - Joy Walsh (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - "Where Did This Guy Cone From Anyway?"-Gerald Nicosia (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - "The Brothers Martin or The Decline of America"-Regina Weinreich (Box 12, Folder 19)